[
    {
        "question": "Ðæt maden (<em>bitan</em>) #### alcne ðe heo geracan mihte — The maiden bit anything she could reach",
        "correctAnswer": "bat",
        "explanation": "Here 'bitan' is in the third person singular past form '<em>bat</em>' because the subject is 'Ðæt maden'",
        "commonMistakes": []
    },
    {
        "question": "Mycel yfel deð se ðe leas (<em>writan</em>) #### — Much evil does he who writes falsely",
        "correctAnswer": "writ",
        "explanation": "Here 'writan' is in the third person singular present form '<em>writ</em>' because the subject is 'se'",
        "commonMistakes": []
    },
    {
        "question": "Ðu (<em>ripan</em>) #### ðine æceras — You reap your acres",
        "correctAnswer": "ripst",
        "explanation": "Here 'ripan' is in the second person singular present form '<em>ripst</em>' because the subject is 'Ðu'",
        "commonMistakes": []
    },
    {
        "question": "Ða ealdan preostas cealf (<em>sniþan</em>) #### — The old priests slaughtered a calf",
        "correctAnswer": "snidon",
        "explanation": "Here 'sniþan' is in the third person plural past form '<em>snidon</em>' because the subject is 'Ða ealdan preostas'",
        "commonMistakes": []
    },
    {
        "question": "He ofer sæ (<em>liþan</em>) #### in Gallia rice — He travelled over the sea to the Kingdom of the Gauls",
        "correctAnswer": "laþ|lað",
        "explanation": "Here 'liþan' is in the third person singular past form '<em>laþ</em>' because the subject is 'He'",
        "commonMistakes": []
    },
    {
        "question": "Gif we eow ða gastlican sad sawaþ, hwonlic biþ ðæt we eowere flaslican þing (<em>ripan</em>) #### — If we sow the spiritual seeds for you, it is little matter that we reaped your fleshly goods",
        "correctAnswer": "ripon",
        "explanation": "Here 'ripan' is in the plural past form '<em>ripon</em>' because the subject is 'we'",
        "commonMistakes": []
    },
    {
        "question": "Hwilum ic on wloncum wicge (<em>ridan</em>) #### — Sometimes I ride on a proud horse",
        "correctAnswer": "ride",
        "explanation": "Here 'ridan' is in the first person singular present form '<em>ride</em>' because the subject is 'ic'",
        "commonMistakes": []
    },
    {
        "question": "Hie (<em>bidan</em>) #### Drihtnes domes — They await the Lord's doom",
        "correctAnswer": "bidaþ|bidað",
        "explanation": "Here 'bidan' is in the plural form '<em>bidaþ</em>' because the subject is 'hie'",
        "commonMistakes": []
    },
    {
        "question": "Ða wicingas (<em>drifan</em>) #### us to ðære sæ — The Vikings drive us to the sea",
        "correctAnswer": "drifaþ|drifað",
        "explanation": "Here 'drifan' is in the third person singular present form '<em>drifaþ</em>' because the subject is 'Ða wicingas'",
        "commonMistakes": []
    },
    {
        "question": "Heofenes gim (<em>glidan</em>) #### ofer grundas — Heaven's gem glided over the earth",
        "correctAnswer": "glad",
        "explanation": "Here 'glidan' is in the third person singular past form '<em>glad</em>' because the subject is 'Heofenes gim'",
        "commonMistakes": []
    },
    {
        "question": "Se bera on ðæm wudu (<em>scitan</em>) #### — The bear defecated in the woods",
        "correctAnswer": "scat",
        "explanation": "Here 'scitan' is in the third person singular past form '<em>scat</em>' because the subject is 'Se bera'",
        "commonMistakes": []
    },
    {
        "question": "An ðeof ofer þone geard (<em>stigan</em>) #### ond stæll þa wyrta — A thief climbed over the hedge and stole the plants",
        "correctAnswer": "stag",
        "explanation": "Here 'stigan' is in the third person singular past form '<em>stag</em>' because the subject is 'An ðeof'",
        "commonMistakes": []
    },
    {
        "question": "Heo (<em>bidan</em>) #### soþra gehata — She awaited faithful promises",
        "correctAnswer": "bad",
        "explanation": "Here 'bidan' is in the third person singular past form '<em>bad</em>' because the subject is 'Heo'",
        "commonMistakes": []
    },
    {
        "question": "Hie (<em>drifan</em>) #### hine onweg — They drove him away",
        "correctAnswer": "drifon",
        "explanation": "Here 'drifan' is in the plural form '<em>drifon</em>' because the subject is 'Hie'",
        "commonMistakes": []
    },
    {
        "question": "Ðeos bat (<em>glidan</em>) #### on laguflode — This boat glides over the ocean",
        "correctAnswer": "glitt",
        "explanation": "Here 'glidan' is in the third person singular present form '<em>glit</em>' because the subject is 'Ðeos bat'",
        "commonMistakes": [
            {
                "incorrectAnswer": "glidþ",
                "explanation": "Don't forget, whenever conjugation produces '<strong>dþ</strong>', it is changed to '<strong>tt</strong>' so 'glidan' becomes 'glitt'"
            },
            {
                "incorrectAnswer": "glidð",
                "explanation": "Don't forget, whenever conjugation produces '<strong>dþ</strong>', it is changed to '<strong>tt</strong>' so 'glidan' becomes 'glitt'"
            }
        ]
    },
    {
        "question": "(<em>bitan</em>) #### hine lys — Lice bit him",
        "correctAnswer": "biton",
        "explanation": "Here 'bitan' is in the plural past form '<em>biton</em>' because the subject is 'lys'",
        "commonMistakes": []
    },
    {
        "question": "Edmund þis boc (<em>writan</em>) #### — Edmund wrote this book",
        "correctAnswer": "wrat",
        "explanation": "Here 'writan' is in the third person singular past form '<em>wrat</em>' because the subject is 'Edmund'",
        "commonMistakes": []
    },
    {
        "question": "Ða hie heora corn (<em>ripan</em>) #### — When they reaped their grain",
        "correctAnswer": "ripon",
        "explanation": "Here 'ripan' is in the plural past form '<em>ripon</em>' because the subject is 'hie'",
        "commonMistakes": []
    },
    {
        "question": "Heo mec (<em>sniþan</em>) #### seaxes ecg — She cut me with the blade of the knife",
        "correctAnswer": "snaþ|snað",
        "explanation": "Here 'sniþan' is in the third person singular present form '<em>snaþ</em>' because the subject is 'Heo'",
        "commonMistakes": []
    },
    {
        "question": "We ofer laguflode scipas (<em>liþan</em>) #### — We sailed ships over the ocean",
        "correctAnswer": "lidon",
        "explanation": "Here 'liþan' is in the plural past form '<em>lidon</em>' because the subject is 'We'",
        "commonMistakes": []
    },
    {
        "question": "Sum mon (<em>ridan</em>) #### be ðære stowe — A certain man rode to the holy place",
        "correctAnswer": "rad",
        "explanation": "Here 'ridan' is in the third person singular past form '<em>rad</em>' because the subject is 'Sum mon'",
        "commonMistakes": []
    }
]
